In Marvelous Designer, you can express various fabrics through texture and physical properties.
I believe you can do the texture processing in many software.
Now we will show you how to control the texture of the fabric by adjusting the physical properties of the fabric.
First, in Marvelous Designer, you can choose the physical properties of the fabric.
The first word in the name of the physical property represents the composition of the material.
For example, cotton is cotton, denim is denim, wool is wool, etc.
When you use different fabrics, the texture of the clothing will change.
For example, leather will be harder.
If you use silk, it will be harder.
If you use cotton, it will be harder.
The second word in the name of the physical property represents the composition of the fabric.
The first word in the name of the physical property represents the composition of the fabric.
In Marvelous Designer, you can choose the physical properties of the fabric.
For example, leather will be harder.
For example, cotton is cotton, denim is denim, wool is wool, etc.
You can also use denim lightweight for your clothes.
Knit-bonded jersey can be used for thick, soft pleated shirts.
Polister taffeta can be used to cover the outer layer of your clothes.
These are some of the fabrics that you will often use in the process of making clothes.
When modeling, you can first use the default fabric to make clothes, and then change the fabric.
In addition to the preset fabric properties, we can also adjust the details and physical properties of the fabric at the bottom.
The physical properties of the fabric are divided into gold, tail, and corner lines.
You can use 2D window panels.
Use the 2D tool to check the direction of the fabric sand line.
The arrow direction is the gold of the fabric, and the vertical direction is the tail of the fabric.
The diagonal direction is the direction of the diagonal line.
The vertical direction is the direction of the diagonal line.
First, understand the strength of gold sand and the strength of the diagonal line.
The strength of gold sand will mainly affect the stretching performance of the fabric.
The strength of the diagonal line is the stretching performance of the diagonal line.
When the intensity is increased, the fabric will stretch more easily, so it is easy to create creases.
If the intensity is reduced, the fabric will stretch more easily, so the clothing will become longer, and it is not easy to maintain the creases that have already been created.
The higher the bending intensity, the thicker the fabric looks, and the more puffy the sewing position looks.
The fabric looks more like the texture of leather.
The lower the bending intensity, the softer the fabric looks, and the texture is closer to silk.
The bending intensity represents the degree to which the fabric is deformed.
The lower the bending intensity, the harder it is to deform, so the creases are easier to maintain.
The higher the bending intensity, the harder it is to deform, so the creases are harder to maintain.
When the bending intensity is changed to 100,
the creases in the sewing would disappear.
In fact, the fabric will definitely shrink after forming creases.
When the fabric is bent, the creases are reduced to the degree to which they can deform,
or the bending intensity is reduced to the degree to which the creases are not.
The lower the bending intensity, the faster the creases are reduced.
You can control the overall effect of a fabric by using these attributes.
This is a sample of the fabric.
The fabric is made of a soft material.